Kyle Downey

QA Engineer

Oak Lawn, IL

github.com/kylefdowney (708) 710-3471

kylefdowney@gmail.com

Summary

I am a proficient QA Engineer with experience writing Jest and Puppeteer browser tests, and also web development experience building JavaScript applications using frameworks like React and Angular.

Skills

QA / Web Development

HTML / CSS, JavaScript, Jest, Puppeteer, Selenium, React, Angular, ¡Query, Git, SQL, Python

User Experience Design

Responsive Design, Wireframes, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects

Education

Chicago Coding Temple

2017

Accelerated course on JavaScript, Angular, jQuery, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Web API's, & Bootstrap UI

Illinois State University

2015 - 2017

Bachelor of Science in Arts Technology – 3.7 GPA

Professional Experience

Podverse 2020

QA Intern

- Writing automated tests for the Podverse web application using JavaScript, Jest, and Puppeteer.
- Performed quality assurance testing on React Native apps on iOS and Android.
- Updated and maintained the database to add new podcasts as requested by users.

Garfield Building Maintenance

2019 - 2020

Webmaster

• Designed, programmed, and deployed a new static website for Garfield Building Maintenance.

Weaver Consultants Group

2018

Software Support Specialist

- Developed a PHP web app to analyze readings and data-trends from excel files containing site data.
- Assisted coworkers from all departments in computer and Active Directory related troubleshooting.

ISU's College of Arts and Sciences IT

2016 - 2017

Web Developer / Project Manager

- Managed the development of new and existing university websites and their features.
- Led new employees on onboarding procedures and designated tasks.

Portfolio

QA Automated Tests

• Repo: github.com/podverse/podverse-ga/tree/master/podverse-web/ tests

Video Game Portal

- Demo: kylefdowney.github.io/GameAPI/
- Repo: github.com/kylefdowney/GameAPI

Various Projects

- Demo: kylefdowney.github.io/kfdportfolio
- Repo: github.com/kylefdowney/kfdportfolio